[Music]
welcome to our board meeting
this is probably infinity now i think
numbers
and uh today we're on like number three
of the foundational document though
where we are talking about our values
and i did get confused last week because
i was like i'll take a quiz and i
realized it was like oh not our personal
values
our collective company values
and so that is yes very different so i
don't know if anyone else had a chance
to sit with the
values they would like to bring to it
but i wrote down a couple things
all of which are a little a little big
goodness is one
it's kind of like google's don't be evil
like the good thing is number one
and then other ones follow underneath
yeah i the only i
i thought about this a little bit but
not as much as i'd hoped to
um
so i i know we want to have some things
in there like you know
like omni when it's really kind of value
um
you know everything we do kind of
benefits everybody but um
or at least doesn't hurt everybody
it doesn't hurt anybody um
so but like sovereignty individual
sovereignty although i think we need to
define that
at some point um because there are
several meanings for that
but i didn't get much further than
that
from mutual support maybe yeah
i think like last week when we went
through what omni win was
like what that kind of definition was
and who the who the stakeholders were i
think that
is us defining omni win which i think
was very powerful
uh and i also have like goodness in
quotations i just have anti-rival risks
because
that is part of the goodness is anything
that kind of fits within that category
is something that
just being it is a reward and also
having other people be it as a reward
but it's it's a lot in there
right it is the omni-win and the
anti-rival and
those things and it's like if we're not
being that first then why anything else
anyway but also
transparency is one that comes up
consistently
uh in all of our projects that there
needs to be transparency for trust
and then um innovation that we do need
to grow
both as individuals hopefully but mainly
as a project right like if we
even if we created the best amazing
together tech omni win thing for our
projects
if it's not growing or it's not inviting
in new projects which itself would be
growth
not growth for growth's sake in game a
but if it's not growing it's dying right
i mean that
in a very nature-based way innovation
um and i think i already said it maybe i
skipped this one that it's fun but it's
an enjoyable thing that we are doing so
that it is
something we want to keep keep going
back to
i'm not sure how to phrase it this part
but i think there needs to be some
element of like
i don't know effectiveness or like for
example
the mec thing right where like you could
tell they had some good values they were
working towards stuff
but they weren't effective they built
something that people couldn't afford
and so they just got sold and so that
sort of undermines their entire
purpose um yeah and so something around
like effectiveness or pragmatism
or you know like actually making
meaningful progress
um
[Music]
yeah effectiveness kind of is innovation
meets
goodness right because it's like if
we're if we're just being
good but we're not doing anything that's
not helpful it's not innovative we're
just being innovative or breaking things
that's not great
it's like effective is exactly what you
said with mec
like it doesn't matter if you make the
most um
beautiful company if no one's gonna shop
there including the membership because
the prices are too high
that is part of it and in the
transparency giving people the
information
right that we're not the board of mech
trying to keep secrets or trying to like
get the
highest price point or the lowest um
whatever that we're
giving the full picture and then saying
so it's like are we going to be this
part are we are we going to be this with
the lowest price point are we going to
be this with the medium or this with the
highest price point right and letting
people pick but like
pick for where you're actually going to
shop not for your
lofty ideals that you're never going to
actually stand behind
right and like i think it's it just
ended up being a hybrid but i think it
is unique in this list so far because if
you can have something that's good and
innovative but it's not like it's
it's not useful or it's too expensive
people won't actually buy it
right or what whatever and it also gets
weird because like
these are the values of the project
which is really just a collection of
other projects kind of
like a way to help those projects move
forward so some of these may not
actually end up being the together tech
values but just like
values that we recommend others have
yeah and what's what's also interesting
about this is i find when we're going
through this
it's not like a typical company where
you can very narrowly
define what it is the
the sub purpose the main purpose of this
organization is just that everyone has a
better world to live in
it so
you know it's it's very very broad much
broader than
the simple thing of saying let's make a
profit
um so so yeah you get into this much
more complex and and the values are
are often much broader than you would
for a normal
group right i think also because this
project is kind of all about doing it
it's kind of secondhand
like in theory right it's the projects
like race and score and wikilection and
solution raising
and hyper logos and all of those are
gonna are gonna make the actual
changes and this is just about trying to
help them
it's just about how can we make those
groups be as you know
have all the resources that they need
whether that's you know time
money experience skills etc um
and like for me and all of this that's
one of the things i kept
hitting as a block is like i'd be like
oh this i'm like oh no that that's more
value like for converti or wiki election
and not
together tech so i kept kind of having
that battle on is this to do with
my projects or to do with the group
project of together tech
and you know the project projects well
throw some of those out
was it like you know being able to
choose your right politician and that's
definitely wikilection or what
what were some of those examples um for
mine a lot of it
i guess was more on the converting side
because i think that that's where
there's a lot more of the the bleed over
and then you know it's things like
sort of um presenting
how the word this like useful
information to make a decision
sort of or like you know fighting
misinformation
um i guess a lot of it centers around
just
those two are fighting this information
and then presenting information in a way
that helps people sort of get a summary
and decide one way or the other
yeah and that that's um
you're right that's more comfortable
though that made me think is that do we
have a value
of creating documentation
so people can self learn or
or is that implying that we don't have a
value of direct
mentorship or do we value both and then
maybe we don't need to say it because
really that all just falls under
education and training
right so that's a way of like
i mean this is too long to put down but
like maximizing the content and thought
leadership that we make for multiple
learning styles
or however we want to say that right
like sort of the
the stuff that is made is meant for
because right now
game a like if you're a successful
gaming entrepreneur you largely fit into
sort of
one type of thing like
a lot of them are going to have a lot of
similarities but whereas at least i've
noticed the game b personality is
very different like it's kind of all the
other ones that fall
to the side in game a have kind of found
a home here and then it's them trying to
figure out how to work together
one thing that is a value i have on a
lot of my projects which i think
supporting multiple learning styles
is talking about but has been so
co-opted by the left that no one hears
it for what it is diversity
right that like what we need is
diversity somebody coming to the table
being different than us
is actually really powerful in like in
those learning styles right
if we only wanted to bring in visual
learners that's going to hurt us whereas
if we have that diversity there
then um different people can contribute
in different ways as long as the group
can hold that and not require
everyone has to be this effective
everyone has to have this level of fun
everyone has to have
this level of transparency tmi all over
the place everybody
right that's that's diversity not
opinion people culture of race
that's interesting because to me the
other part that i think of when i think
of
diversity in terms of together tech is
something that i'm not sure
everyone agrees with in the space which
is kind of like internal competition
like i really care about misinformation
so i don't want wiki election and con
variety to be the only projects
i want there to be more reason scores
and like uh how there to be 20 projects
to deal with misinformation
we all sort of you know work together
where necessary but then also say
well no that's my you know that's what
differentiates khan ferrari from reason
score
so let's keep them different but still
work together wherever possible
so that in the end we've got 20
people in that race yeah and i don't
know
i don't know where this fits but it's
very similar to that there's a big
difference between
like recent squirt and wiki election
were both like your babies and came to
the table versus something we might
create together
and um whether it's brought by one
person or we create it together
there's a difference between saying back
to the drawing board start again whether
it's in competition coopetition
or whether it's an iteration right
maybe comparati like the stuff that's
underneath ooh i could use that over
here right so there's that um
having redundancy is good that there's
multiple projects
and there's a way to kind of like split
and merge
right that there's like merging the
technology much more difficult
but maybe that's 4.0 right like how
would we bring the
election and reason score together right
yeah i don't know i think
more to that point a lot of these
projects will end up with some sort
of a shared data source that i think at
least to start with we would restrict
you can only use the shared data source
if you're a part of this
ecosystem right like you can't be
microsoft or google and come in and
start using it
because odds are aren't going to have
the same kind of apis and stuff like
that
and we may never it may only be open to
people that say you know we operate
at least based on some of these values
and we're not going to you know
steal it or you know try to monetize it
unethical ways
yeah i think that's really good
brainstorming
i think so too that's pretty we got a
lot
because part of the point of doing
values is to be able to say
this is our first value if it breaks it
we're not doing it
great now we go on to the second one
right and somehow having that hierarchy
of values well at the same time
that it's a living breathing thing right
maybe like we we've defined omni-win as
it being it benefit to everyone right
it's it moves everyone forward but it
might move
one person stays the same and everyone
else takes a powerful report right that
there's
wiggle room within that but you don't
get to be google and be like
we don't do evil and then unless it's
for profit
unless it's scrap that is our motto
right we'd have to describe that as our
motto
and having i think we did lay it out in
our mission and vision that omni-win
kind of is our number one
and then part of that is breaking that
down into
and i don't even know if we can do it in
the foundational documents i think it
actually is coming up against
the issues as they arise but the more we
could get it here the better
does anyone want to change any ordering
because like you said the values i think
are helpful to be in a
explicit order yeah
i mean i guess i'd like to see
sustainability higher maybe
and actually some of these are will will
probably combine
like you were saying goodness exactly
goodness is kind of a
a larger bucket do we want to keep
goodness in
or like explicitly called out or what do
you think jubilee now that you've
thought about
i'm good with it but it was it was just
my place holder for things like
and sustainable and like all of the who
would want it to be
less sustainable right like we wanted to
have that goodness
baked in and omni wind does get that i
like
i mean transparency to me is a very high
value because i don't think we get a lot
of the other ones without it
but it's also if it hurts omni when we
don't do transparency
right but other than that we have
transparency same with i'm willing to
break a lot like
i don't need fun 24 7 but if i'm showing
up consistently and there's a lot of
drama and there's a lot of conflict and
it's like zero fun
i'm not gonna keep coming and i know
therefore whatever we're doing isn't
continually happen not because i'm not
there because everyone's gonna not be
there right if it's not fun
so those are just my to me effectiveness
is
is is one of the top more because it's
kind of that
gray area where like we talked about you
know if something is omnivore and the
goal is to never
cause harm well what if you're causing
less harm than the current alternative
you're still causing harm but you're
lessening it yeah i'm just
i'm just wondering whether effectiveness
is
kind of a summary of omni-whim
and sustainability resistance resilience
long-term thinking i mean can we
i think effectiveness it's more the
trade-off between the values
in a way right like it's if if we looked
at all of the values we're saying hey
it really improves these values it kind
of hurts this value a little bit
but much less than we're improving the
other ones to me that
that's okay because it's moving things
forward i mean it might depend on what
these specifics are
but overall that's i guess what i'm
trying to
and maybe it's not a value maybe that
ends up being a strategy or a tactic
or something but to me like really
mec is one of the best examples of sort
of why that shows or you know
any group where you you you're well
intentioned
but you're so dogmatic that like you
actually end up hurting your cause
because you can't move forward
yeah let me just kind of pull
effectiveness out
sure to a whole discussion because
i think you're right it's it it
has something to do with the values but
it seems
it's like how strict we are with the
values not necessarily value itself kind
of
yeah so let's just
kind of pull it out maybe discuss that
separately
so for me individual sovereignty
although i know unders i understand now
how it is in game b and i think that i
embody it quite well
i always get triggered by it because it
makes me think that i have to garden and
i have to do everything on my own and
part of this
is that we're better together yes you
don't ever have to pass
you don't ever have to give up your
sovereignty but that doesn't mean
you're an island like there's a
difference between
individuals yeah because when i was
thinking about this i
also kind of have a value of
responsibility which is even
harsher way of saying what you don't
want but you
are even more triggering right um and i
don't really want that to be
a obligation but i want it to be a skill
that we have right so i couldn't figure
out how to say that but i never really
thought of
individual sovereignty being triggering
in that way but so but i understand
the concern um and i'm wondering
technically does
doesn't omni does omni women include
individual sovereignty
i mean i think it does yeah i think much
like also the omni-win values needing to
be played off each other and we have to
figure out as we go is this omni one is
a little bit effective
that's also the case with individual
sovereignty of like
are you more sovereign this year than
you were last year awesome
not that you know what i mean like
arbitrary branch because i can be more
sovereign than i am now i just am never
going to be able to live off the land
all by myself
those are very different i think
sovereignty goes
up to the win list like i think that's
one of the wins is if we improve
the sovereignty of the people involved
that is um one of the people involved in
the meta community discussion we were
having on mondays
one has that as um felice i can't
remember the name of the rest of their
the name of their company they're
their group but that's what they're
that's their whole point of their
community is to help people with their
sovereignty like you are as a parent to
help your kid become independent
i really like that as as how he explains
it and i'm
down with that level of sovereignty
whenever you are can we get can we
improve it for you
in a way that works for you what would
get you more sovereign
right yeah it's all kind of freedom
right
and the right to control your destiny as
much as possible
um do we think that the number three is
also contained in omni one the
sustainability the resilience
i was yeah i'm thinking that because we
i think we do have we have long term
up here already yeah um
i think we said that like environment is
sort of
needed for being so that was kind of in
the
the only yeah the only reason i might
want to separate them out is that
in omniwin it's the long-term
benefits of the of the individuals
beings when we're here it's
long-term sustainability of the
um of the
organization itself okay so that's the
only reason why i think it might be a
little bit different
although now i'm thinking i want to be
sure that we would never
sacrifice any of the other values in
order to get
sustainability because if if suddenly we
don't need this organization
we need to shut it down right you know
what i'm saying if it does this job
if we cure you know if the organization
was for curing
hunger we shouldn't keep people starving
so we can keep serving them right
which some organizations
and accidentally are doing that
right they're not solving the core
problem because they would be out of a
job and i don't think anyone's doing
that intentionally but
um it's kind of weird how when the
incentives are that way you accidentally
perpetuate what you're
solving so i don't know how to write all
that down
so there's something coming up because
when you said say the sustainability i
was actually thinking you were talking
about the planet
and that that i mean that like us making
sure our planet is taken care of is like
priority
one and then and there's something about
that right if we don't have an
earth to work on until we're in space
that's kind of priority one
not from earth right but i think that
all fits under omni when
but i think i think we want to call out
the organ we want to think long term
also when we're
unless we just want to blanket please
state that the organization itself is
included in omni-win
but it's not in a way because we will
shut down the organization if it's no
longer needed
right yeah would mention the
organization can harm if it helps
everyone else
yeah the the what i'm trying to say is
the hierarchy of that sustainability
right that there is that earth the earth
is number one
right like even though we might make
individual choices that are not going to
benefit the earth
we need the long term to be like okay
long term is this gonna
and then it's weird because we need the
the together tech in order to have the
projects in order to
help the people but it's actually the
people that is next right it's like
earth people if we're not serving the
people
our projects don't need the help this
can shut down and so it's
yeah i don't know yeah i mean there's is
a slight difference between priority of
importance and priority of order of
operations
so the people are technically more
important because we did have a second
earth
we'd be okay if something happened to
one but
you have to work on fixing the earth
first so that the people can survive
um yeah
i think in my case i don't think that if
we had a second earth it's suddenly okay
to
say screw this one because i care about
animals you're saying if you had to kill
half the people
to save the earth you would choose to
move to the second earth
the it's just priority of what's more
important the people are actually more
important but the earth
maybe have to do what you work on first
to save the people
right but you're doing it for the people
you're not technically doing it for the
planet you're doing it
for the people right yeah
yeah if we say beings i'm comfortable
with that because yes
not really people although some people's
pets are
people yeah well it's and that's sort of
the
thing right like i think people are more
than animals but not like infinitely so
not like you know let all the animals
die to save one person
mosquitoes um i i'm fairly certain
we could kill all actually the
mosquitoes that feed on humans
there are a lot of there are some
mosquitoes that don't suck blood of
something anyways so that's complete
there is
is that kind of tied to effectiveness
because that's
really sort of what like either
organization is still going to be around
it can't do its job if it's not that's
kind of the main thing i'm after
when i say effectiveness it's like is it
effective is it doing it is it still
going to be here is it fulfilling its
purpose
um to me that's kind of all the same
yeah and yeah and maybe it really isn't
a value maybe it's just a strategy
um because we don't really care whether
the organization exists except for the
value the organization is buying but the
the the organization existing itself
isn't
a value it's the value the organization
creates right
so i think this ordering of values makes
sense because omniwin is first and so is
law
and then it's organizational
sustainability so like we do need our
effectiveness we need to still
be here until it's no longer omni-win
for us to be here
transparency helps in that right if it's
gonna hurt the
effectiveness or it's gonna hurt the
omni when we don't do it otherwise we do
do it
and fun being you know like yes we can
do all of that and have fun but let's do
fun
like a lot of fun uh you know like i
think that
i like the top four so far transparency
also seems like
another one where if we could somehow
make game b
and not do it in a transparent way like
i don't think it would work
but i think if you could you know wave a
magic wand and have this organization go
with all these resources but
the magic wand wasn't transparent
like there's still like it kind of to me
fits a bit in the same group as
wherever we end up putting effectiveness
where it's sort of like that's one of
the things that we think that we need to
do to be able to get there to be able to
stay
you know have the organization stay and
exist and be trustworthy
um but to me i'm not sure if it's a
value
yeah i i think i mean we have more time
to talk about this but i think we're
someone needs to kind of sit down and
take all this in
and kind of figure out a structure that
works because there isn't a lot of hard
and fast rules about what's a value and
what's uh
what's a mission what's a vision because
they
they tend to overlap some and then we
have like strategies
and where you put things is kind of
can flow a bit um but just kind of
thinking of a way to
organize it coherently
because i don't even know if these are
royal
values i'm trying to think of there's
another
we do we do value these things but
you know we value the mission and the
vision as well yeah
and i think a lot of them to your point
a lot of them end up being a combination
of things that we've kind of already
said
like diversity is kind of a combination
of omni-win and effectiveness
as we're saying like we want to be nice
to the people and include them we also
think that we're going to end up being
better off for it
yeah so i'm not sure if that's a value
or again a strategy slash
kind of a part of well if we're saying
omni
by definition that involves everyone so
that's kind of diverse but then the
strategy is let's make sure that we
include those opinions
and like let's be honest some of our
projects are decidedly not diverse
yeah it's funny i'd i've worked with
some
in some businesses and they talk about a
lot of times the values do end up being
these kind of like generic things and
that's
how you know you're doing it wrong
because what you're supposed to be
talking about is what's a unique value
to your company not
just the general values of the people in
but in this case once again
we're it's a first thing it's a project
of projects
so it's going to be more generic and
then it's
also it exists
to support kind of this game b
philosophy so it's going to include a
lot of
that so it's we're we're going to end up
breaking
that right i think that's an important
point so there's sort of the two sides
to it there's the
organization itself and like how we
think that it can sort of best
facilitate
what values it does have to have to be
effective and for people to trust it
but i think it also ends up being used
as like a checklist for
should we work with that project
like if it you know agrees with one of
the values is that good
if it did you know disagrees with all
the values that you know if shell oil
shows up and wants to participate but
not change any of the ways it operates
probably not going to
yeah i'm still trying to figure out if
transparency it's a
zone value because it's so integral to
everything i'm trying to do
and yet it like would i be okay if i
woke up tomorrow we were living in game
b but there was no transparency or it
was like
just internal information to a
absolutely my absolute favorite people's
board like board of directors and i
still need there to be trans like i'm
still no matter how benevolent that
group is
and however much i don't want to touch
the data and i don't want to watch all
of the board meetings
i want to be able to and i don't know
whether that's just me right in my own
crap that i can
like there's something about
transparency that gives us
everything else but as individuals as
projects and as meta
that it is and yet sometimes it needs to
not be there
when it's going to hurt the
organizational sustainability before and
if it's you know not hurting omni went
or it is hurting omni-win then it needs
to not be there but otherwise it has to
be
that the that it's um the default
otherwise it's so easy to be like oh i
don't want to put myself out there so
yeah let's just do this closed door
let's just do this in this way um
and then it becomes like parent-child
relationship right like someone who
is a barrier to that information but
i'm open to it being part of it because
i think i hear what you're saying it's
the same as effectiveness
but there's something about it that it
is bigger than effectiveness
because it's like whether we fail or
whether even if we're horribly
ineffective if we're transparent the
next ones can learn
right yeah i think if it's not
technically a value it's good to have it
on there because
people know that's an expectation what
if we want to start a separate list like
for strategies
that there's like you know focusing on
it
effectiveness that might even be a bit
too broad for strategies but like
transparency definitely seems like a
strategy we're like okay that's one of
the things that we could do to help this
there are things that won't be
transparent but overall one of our
goals is to have it be as transparent as
possible so that people trust us and so
that you know if it fails
the next group can pick it up etc
i mean i'm okay with it going under this
new beautiful blue effectiveness one
that it is part of that right that
effectiveness is about strategy
right right so having transparency
having profitability or resource
whatever you want
we have to be able to be in business to
stay in business while game a is still
here
having that you know having people work
with their passion but what
jobs need to get done so how are we
going to get the jobs done that nobody
wants to do
right that effectiveness that
i can talk tech and game b all day if
the stuff won't get because this goes
more down
it's really just saving like the final
value is just going to be on me
that's okay took us three weeks to get
there four weeks
i'm also thinking we're kind of at our
limit of maybe what we can do ourselves
that the rest of like the currencies and
those kind of things would probably be
beneficial to have
um raymond here either next week or we
could go one more week
without where we're kind of trying to
figure out the currencies and trying to
figure out that stuff
maybe based on um
protocol.love right on their website um
they break down the currencies and so
possibly doing that
how are we feeling do we want raymond
here or
like for to be the expert in that not
just one of one of us
and to be to be here um holding that
space for that
or do we want to give us one more week
and it was still half an hour but
i think we could go really either way
maybe just see what his availability is
um yeah i think we could go down
further and then um through that
discussion
we'll be able to come back and kind of
clean these up
because i think we know what we want we
just don't know how to say it
yeah we all seem very much in alignment
with our confusion on exactly how to say
it
like we're not disagreeing right right
horrible transparency
yeah it's yeah it's just kind of how to
phrase it now to express it where who
are aligned in the concepts
level
do you have anything to add i think
you're muted
you are muted you weren't before but you
are now ah that's why i
um i'm making noises
we're giving everyone the silent
treatment for the first
that's our highest value that's only one
so i uh i thought about values uh
and i was thinking in slightly different
way um
the way being more general uh
because i kind of i thought that values
should be
um very like
uh the foundation which
can be really uh philosophically
simple and the
values define the mode in which we
operate
and uh very high
uh level abstract well not abstract but
it's like okay um the first value uh
that i would have although is
not easy to explain um
but i was lucky to have it explained
long time ago
like a long way so uh
the most basic value to me uh that
exists
and from which everything else uh
comes out of is
the truth basically uh and i know it may
sound very uh vague and uh it's
an overloaded term but truth as in
adherence to reality
and being in touch with reality is like
the basis
because without it uh we don't really
know what omni win wins what
fun is what uh support us what uh
innovation it needs to be grounded in
reality itself
despite the fact that uh these days
people
tend to think in terms of opinions and
that
reality is dependable on uh individual
uh like window of perception and stuff
like that
uh which is true of course obviously and
then again everything is void anyway so
uh our state of mind is
something we could talk about ad noise
[Music]
and it's a fine subject to talk about
but still
um there is a consensual reality
in which we all live and which we all
create together
for me that's a fact and um
opinions exist and different points of
view obviously exist
and uh they all come together to create
this one reality
and this one reality is actually real
like physically real in some sense and
the sense is
important enough for me to put truth and
adherence to reality at the first place
and from that
like everything else everything else
depends actually on reality existing
so that's my like um
[Music]
yeah and because uh
again reality is the like highest um
it's not judgmental but it's the um
adherence to reality is also uh like
um what gives you um
it's the ultimate uh
uh what's the word um
that's why we say things like reality
check
if something is uh like far away from
reality uh it may
fail and sometimes no one knows why
something failed but
the reason could be that it was unglued
disconnected from reality that's also
expression we use
and yeah it's just important
and um
and what irritates us if i may say us
in game a is that is it is so
game a is so full of and
advertisement and it seems like uh
yeah the basic truth is so um
undervalued these days and it's just so
boring and so so tedious and
um for me and i just realized that today
gaming is like a search for
more reality and being more grounded in
what we have
yeah so i have a lot of thoughts on that
but i wonder if you want to go ahead and
get
are there any other values that you want
to
suggest that build on that or is that
the main thing you want to add
that was the main thing and then i was
going to
no i wasn't going to say anything about
uh our
as species our place on
the planet and in biosphere but that
would be something i would
i could talk about for long so yeah
let's leave it
uh i mean i agree that truth is kind of
the core
of everything um
and that that kind of um
you know the the the more accurate you
are
in your judgment of reality
the better things will be um
the more accurate their interpretation
of reality be the better things would be
but
um i don't know if that fits as a value
of the organization itself
because i don't think the organization
will be
seeking to clarify
that um
i mean that that's part of the reason
score project i think adrian would say
that's part of wiki election
um but i don't know that
this that this project that we would get
in go down to that
depth is my opinion i don't know what
everyone else thinks well it's coming up
for me
with um radica i both am like yes the
truth is very important adherence to
reality and at the same time
that is the biggest existential
question right like what is true and
what does that mean is it collective
truth and then i have to toe the line
is it is it scientific truth like right
now with the
with the virus the pandemic there's a
truth to how it functions
we've got no say in it it doesn't care
about our democracy it doesn't care
about anything it's a virus
that's just doing what it's doing and
there's a truth to how it does right
it's in
its ingestion period it's incubation
period how many people you infect all of
that is just is what it is
and then there's like people's
interpretation of that and the doctors
and like the experts truth and it's like
that can change
yet the virus isn't changing the virus
is also changing but its truth isn't
right and so that is part of the
like looking at things like that whereas
then you have the less truth right where
it's like
black lives matter and and all and it's
like if you question
anything about that you're the devil
right and it's like that's not a truth
i'm trying to find more truth here
more truth and it you know what i mean
it's it's breaking it and so holding it
as just like holding sovereignty or
something as your number one value
is powerful and then how do you actually
live that out helps you in all the other
values
it's just a little more concrete than
omni-win
likes having sovereign dear truth at
that level but the fact that there are
projects that deal with it i think are
pretty
but that was my thinking i think truth
and transparency are sort of you know
end up being two sides of the same
thing where if you're you know but i
think part of it is truth is kind of
implied
where it's like if we're saying that
we're going to do these things well if
you say that you're telling the truth
then i guess two two two two options
exist that you are telling the the truth
that that you're not telling the truth
or that you're lying but then of course
you're going to lie that you're telling
the truth because then what's the point
of the lie otherwise
um so i think it it is important i think
it might end up
sort of being like somehow in the same
grouping as transparency and truth but
then overall
everything that we're putting here we're
implying is true
we're saying you know that i'm doing is
important then we'll do it and that you
know like we're not going to be
operating on a profit motive and that is
going to be fun and that they will
so support each other in theory that's
why we're doing all this because we're
saying that this is true and this is how
we're going to operate
but if it's not true personally i
wouldn't trust it more just because they
said that truth was a value
if if that makes sense
and that is also i don't know i'm
reminded of daniel schwachtenberger's
boron sense making where he does break
down
the truthfulness and all of all of that
information
and doing it in that way but then it's
sorry whoever was talking go ahead it is
this complicated so
there are layers to the true end
and yeah transparency is a part of it it
was just
it's something that struck me uh when
you are talking about
uh transparency what it is exactly that
um
we so uh we like so much about it
uh and i just realized it might be
um at least partially that transparency
brings you closer to understanding uh
the
like reality behind organization for
example
and what really is going on inside and
uh
how people do stuff and yeah and
everything
so transparency is definitely part of
the truth
anything else you wanted to add radicals
potential values or for discussion
um they're pretty good
not really i think that's that's good
i think yeah so i think we should
probably sit with these um
things for a while and kind of reconvene
i mean we could talk we have another 15
minutes we've talked about this or
something else
but i i don't know anything else to add
but i know i
i need to do i need to look over this
list let it marinate
in the brain yeah i think
there are at least a couple more values
that we could probably move down to the
effectiveness list
like the small the small experiments
iterations
that seems like something that that
we're saying we think that this will
help but
you know if it doesn't or we find a
better way than we would
just just you know go forward with
anything that works
um
shares resources and infrastructure i
mean i think that's pretty core i'm not
sure if it's a value but it's
yeah yeah i don't i don't that's part of
the brainstorming i don't know about
that
a lot of these seem like strategies like
things that we
we want to use to achieve our values and
admissions and things that we think will
help
but not necessarily values in themselves
i mean i guess really the point of again
having the value system is to know
if it's not doing one we probably
shouldn't be doing it unless there's a
really really good reason
then going on to number two right and of
course omni when we've already broken
that down last week
is to have that structure so that even
if my ego's involved and my emotions are
involved
it's like right but it broke one it has
nothing to do with you
it's you know that like okay jubilee
doesn't get to create a nominee when mlm
because mlms are not on the win or
whatever
it happens to me right that's that's
the level and fun be number three is
like well if it's helping organizational
sustainability insomnia
then then fun needs to happen i'll force
it
right but like if we're omni when and or
helping the organization
survive it doesn't really matter if it's
fun it should be if we can make it
but yeah i think that makes sense
mutual support
i think that kind of combines with the
like multiple learning styles
project competition shared resources
like those
sort of all seem like the same
thing it also seemed kind of like a
strategy like that one of our strategies
for helping these projects is that we're
going to work together and give them an
ecosystem of you know
shared resources and data and whatever
else
[Music]
to help move that forward so yeah i'm
wondering if also
values are things kind of like
expectations for members
in in the dallas startup ecosystem we
have a give before you get um
value so you're not supposed to come in
and just start promoting your stuff
you're supposed to come and say how can
i help first and then
after a while um so i don't know if if
that
that's an interesting value to think i
don't know if that's too
barbarian but or you know forceful
sounds kind of like a
strategy but also value at the same time
so
also thinking like
i guess you'll almost always have to
break it in the beginning it's like the
you know don't speak until you're spoken
to well then who starts speaking
well yeah that's that is that is a
problem
uh although it's we have four projects
that we're all working on so really it'd
be like come help us on one of them
before we help you
but i think that's not really our ethos
that isn't really how we
roll it's like how can we help you move
forward we're already helping each other
i liked what you um posted bentley in
the game b
projects the idea of having a secondary
project
um as one that you're supporting and i
love that idea one of the things that
comes up to me although i think it's a
high value
that i hold the diversity is an
effectiveness thing
diversity as a placeholder like we want
to say we're diverse
is all game a and like it's it's a lot
of the malware
whereas the point of our diversity is to
be more effective
right it's like if we allow for
different learning styles
different learning styles are going to
come if we allow for the diversity of
the individuals present
we get what they're here to give whereas
if we're using it as that token
diversity then it breaks it and so
anyway that's just what's kind of when i
was reading through the list again is
whether diversity could be moved to
effectiveness but
i don't know yeah i i think that's true
i think that diversity is kind of a
combination of
it's part omni one and part the effect
of this depends like
we're being diverse to you know sort of
be nice into to make sure that we're
including as
as many you know diverse groups in the
you know the grouping of everyone which
should be fairly easy um
but then there's also like we think it's
going to be better for the
actual project and projects is you're
going to get more
insights and you know things that you
wouldn't have learned if it was just
12 white guys and it's also very much
part of like and if it's not
diversity can go at least in the group
right like if you're gonna be more
effective as a group of five white guys
having your conversation then for you
know what i mean forced visual diversity
yeah go be a bunch of white guys i'd
rather be you guys be at that table so i
can be at this one anyway
but if it's hurting effectiveness it's
not forced in that way and so that's
right
like that and to me i think that the
people you get
i think it's absolutely like an
important thing to try to say like hey
this isn't just to show up and word
vomit your sales pitch and then
stop contributing but there might be
some where like a person shows up
and we're all really like that's a
really important project i don't really
care if that person contributes i just
want to see that project
over
yeah and in the case it is go bentley i
was just going to say i think
there's naturally some overlap in these
terms and the way they're generally used
but i think in an exercise like this
they're a little bit more specific
so i think part of our problem is that
we're using the more general terms when
we're thinking about it
so i think it might be good to kind of
look up
how they do this when they do this for
game a businesses
um because i think strategy
is also supposed to be so those tactics
and then their strategy
i think strategies may even generally be
temporary
so i think i think some of these things
we should probably
still keep under values especially since
in some
when we're doing like jubilee was saying
when we're choosing
when they conflict and we need to know
the order they have to all be in one
list so we know the the proper order
um and so that's why i like
having transparently mixed transparency
mixed in with the other values because
we want to know
we're not going to limit
the alumni when or the organization's
sustainability
for transparency
so it's good to have them in a lace
rather than two separate lists
maybe
i think strategies so that the terms i'm
just
yeah i just may need to get some clarity
on
what we're doing it may also be that
like there's a reason that values what
wasn't here in that
it's sort of meant to be encapsulated by
the vision and the mission
but i do like sort of having this as a
separate thought experiment
um where i think in the end like all of
our values should be represented
somewhere in the mission
and the emissions and vision i would
think
um so like both the values actually
ended up in this section
we might just be using as like uh a
checklist to make sure that like is
there anything that we're missing
in mission and values that like oh we
listen to value that's super important
but we aren't seeing it
yeah i think that's part of it when we
come up with one of those top values are
putting them in our mission and vision
our yeah mission and
vision yeah vision vision yeah it's like
that started with v and it hurt my brain
because it was also values
um but that like you know what i mean
like we get together and have fun on our
projects while creating omni-win
solutions
is like right because omni win we've
broken it down last week but that's
gonna be we're constantly coming up with
like oh but it hurts this and it helps
that and that's i think
our benefit is that it's not quite we
get what omni win is
and nothing's ever going to be omni when
omni win especially right now
and so it is about dealing in that
tension and saying oh yep that's hurting
transparency but it's helping
equality and it's helping and and making
sure that these things
are happening on a regular basis omni
when we've already broken it down and we
know
right people trump animals as much as we
love animals the planet
people trumps the planet the planet
anyway it's like we can't live without
the planet
um and even that is like and it's okay
if you don't think that right it's okay
if you actually think the planet's more
important than people you're still
welcome
we're just not to hold that value right
like this is the way we're not going to
work towards your individual value we're
working towards our collective one
i'm doing it that way and we're coming
close to the hour um
i don't know if anyone has anything else
to put in this section but i wanted to
last week during round table we had
talked about um kind of electing someone
to be in the hot seat and i said i would
i would take it on if no one else did i
was wondering if anyone wanted to be in
the hot seat tomorrow
because if not i have a tiny piece of
homework so that i can be in the
hot seat
okay so if i am everyone do everyone
being you guys whoever else is going to
show up
um you can do it in the moment as well
but it is to think about an area of your
life
what your life looks like now what you
would like it to look like and what is
stopping you so that wish obstacle so it
could be relationships it could be your
health it could be what you spend your
time doing
it could be the resources you have
anything along those lines it might be
it'll be different for all of us i'm not
going to give us a
health one tell us how your health is
just anything you want to bring to it
you want to crowdsource
so basically we'll be after we share our
first part of round table we'll be
talking about
our individual lives right and how we
could improve them because that is the
product
that i am working on do you mind
throwing that in the
facebook post either for tomorrow or for
today
yeah so i will i will do it for the
tomorrow one so that people who show up
know to do that and then i'll be in the
hot seat if there isn't someone else to
who comes to do that that would be good
and we'll get to know each other a
little more anyway
yeah that sounds great all right
awesome anything else to add for this
one next week i will see if raymond's
available to come
and otherwise we will continue on trying
to fill out the rest ourselves and
otherwise he will be here to help us
with the currencies
and so i encourage everyone
except for jubilee who gets a pass to
maybe take this and
make a copy of this document and just
try and rewrite it maybe
um i don't know if i'm gonna have the
time to do that that's what i feel like
we should do and then see what we come
up with um
uh i don't know that's just the thought
so
homework if you want that makes sense
because
it seems like it's very uh everything is
very
similar to everything else i mean it's
all good it's just
it seems like um positions of
some of the points are slightly
arbitrary and they would
feel uh very good living under the
values effectiveness
uh higher up in the vision mission
yeah we don't really have a
cohesive kind of uh what's it in the
book when you have
that's a term for it i can't think of it
but yeah there's we need
it needs a kind of a
conceptual framework i think what you're
suggesting bentley although you're right
i probably won't be able to do it
it's powerful because it's a lot of
grayed out this is our kind of
brainstorming as having each person
go through and say if i was making the
final copy here's what my final copy
would look like for these things
and then coming back together and seeing
how those look different and being like
oh radic did the
perfect one we can just use his or crap
so we're not in alignment yeah i think
it'll be
good it just needs some word crafting i
think
all right awesome so that's that
homework is for next friday
and i my homework will be to contact
raymond and um and then tomorrow's
homework i will put
under the round table for tomorrow
all right awesome goodbye facebook and
youtube